Hans Hofmann
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Photographs, circa 1925-1966, undated (Series 6) are of People, Events, Places, Works of Art, and Miscellaneous Subjects; also, Oversize Photographs. People include views of Hofmann alone and with Miz, students, and others; Miz Hofmann; Renate Schmitz Hofmann; and Hofmann family. Also, there are pictures of identified and unidentified individuals and groups. Event recorded are "Forum 49" at Gallery 200, exhibition installations, openings, and ceremonies for honorary degrees awarded Hofmann. Photographs of places include Miz Hofmann's Munich apartment, interior and exterior views of Hofmann's Provincetown house, exterior of the Provincetown school, Hofmann's New York studio, and unidentified houses and landscapes. Travel pictures are of Italy, Mexico, California [?], and unidentified locations. Photographs of works of art by Hofmann are mainly 35-mm color slides of works executed 1935-1965 (unfilmed). There are also photographs of works by other artists and Hofmann students. Teaching materials are photographs of Old Masters paintings, drawings, and Classical sculpture, some marked to indicate line, form, or proportion. Miscellaneous subjects are a dog, cat, and doll; also, cover design for Search for the Real in the Visual Arts. The oversize photographs include portraits of Hans Hofmann and Miz, and works of art by Hofmann students.
Printed Matter, 1930-1978, undated (Series 7), contains articles, essays and a letter to the editor by Hans Hofmann; the remaining material by other authors is categorized by type. Exhibition Catalogs and Related Items (mainly announcements and invitations), 1931-1978, undated, are from group and solo shows that featured the work of Hans Hofmann; also, catalogs and announcements of other artists' exhibitions collected by Hofmann (unfilmed). Newspaper clippings and articles from periodicals include reviews, feature articles, articles with brief references to Hofmann or reproductions of his work, and obituaries. Others are on art-related topics and miscellaneous subjects [unfilmed]. Miscellaneous printed matter includes a variety of items such as brochures about art courses (not Hofmann school), reproductions of works by Hofmann and other artists, book prospectuses, and statements. Art Museum: A Center for Cultural Study, a prospectus showing models and drawings of the proposed University Art Museum, Berkeley, notes the location of its Maria and Hans Hofmann Wing. A Scrapbook, 1944-1962, contains clipping, exhibition reviews, and some catalogs, checklists, and invitations. Nineteen books [unfilmed] mentioning or about Hofmann are a part of this series.
Hans Hofmann's Library (Series 8, unfilmed) of art books and general literature was acquired with his papers. Inscribed and annotated volumes have been retained. Books about or mentioning Hofmann are among Printed Matter (Series 7). All other books and periodicals (376 items) were transferred to the Library of the Smithsonian's American Art Museum.
Estate of Hans Hofmann, 1945-1974, undated (Series 9), consists of records of Hofmann's attorney and co-executor, Robert Warshaw, and includes correspondence and legal documents concerning taxes, the Provincetown house, and miscellaneous business matters.
Papers of Renate Schmitz Hofmann, 1962-1967, undated (Series 10), include notes, correspondence, condolence letters and records regarding Hans Hofmann's funeral, and information about the theft of Hofmann paintings from his Provincetown house in 1966.
Other Hans Hofmann Papers, 1929-1976 (1.65 linear ft.) are owned by The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley (Collection number: BANC MSS 80/27 c). An inventory is available on The Bancroft Library's website at http//www.lib.berkeley.edu/BANC/
Arrangement
The Hans Hofmann papers are arranged into 10 series. Correspondence (Series 1) and Financial Records (Series 4) are arranged alphabetically by folder title. Each of the other series is divided into several subseries, with the arrangement described in detail in the Series Descriptions. Unless noted otherwise, material within each folder is arranged chronologically.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1914-1966, undated (boxes 1-3, reels 5801- 5804)
Series 2: School of Fine Arts Records, 1915-1965, undated (boxes 4-5, reels 5804-5806)
Series 3: Writings, circa 1904-1965, undated (boxes 6-7, 20-21, reels 5806-5808 and unfilmed)
Series 4: Financial Records, 1927-1966, undated (box 7, reel 5808)
Series 5: Miscellaneous Records, 1906-1966, undated (box 8, reels 5808-5809)
Series 6: Photographs, circa 1925-1965, undated (boxes 9 -10, reel 5809)
Series 7: Printed Matter, 1928-1978 and undated (boxes 11-16, reel 5809-5810)
Series 8: Hans Hofmann Library (boxes 16-19, unfilmed)
Series 9: Estate Records, 1945-1974, undated (box 19, reel 5811)
Series 10: Papers of Renate Schmitz Hofmann, 1962-1967, undated (box 19, reel 5811)
Related Material
The holdings of the Archives of American Art include papers and oral history interviews of many former students and friends of Hofmann; among these collections are correspondence, photographs, reminiscences, writings, and printed items relating to Hofmann and his school. Noteworthy is the collection of research material compiled by Tina Dickey concerning Hans Hofmann, 1991-2000, including oral history interviews with 27 former students, a recording of a panel discussion, "Forum 2000: Hans Hofmann, the Painter," held at the Provincetown Art Association and Museum, 2000, and a register of students, 1918-1958 compiled by Dickey. The Lillian Kiesler Papers, 1920s-1990s include records of the Hans Hofmann School of Fine Arts. Researchers are advised to conduct a name search in the Smithsonian Institution Research Information System (SIRIS).
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Names" when they are creators or contributors and under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents.
Subjects:
Hofmann, Maria, 1885-1963; Hofmann, Renate Schmitz, 1930-1992; Hans Hofmann School of Fine Arts
Subjects-Topical:
Art schools -- New York (State) -- New York; Art schools -- Massachusetts -- Provincetown; Abstract expressionism; Painting, Modern -- 20th century -- Study and teaching; Art teachers; Art students -- New York (State) -- New York
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Works of art; Slides (photographs)
Provenance
Renate Schmitz Hofmann, widow of the artist, donated to the Archives of American Art 313 35-mm color slides of work by Hans Hofmann in 1974. The remainder of the collection was a gift of the Estate of Hans Hofmann in 1997. In 2006 additional manuscripts, notes and illustrations for Das Malerbuch: Form und Farbe in der Gestaltung by Hofmann were received from the Renate, Hans and Maria Hofmann Trust.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy. Use of the unmicrofilmed portion requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D. C. research facility.
Alternative Forms Available
The bulk of the collection is available on 35mm microfilm reels 5801-5811 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1914-1966, undated, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-3; 3.0 linear ft.; Reels 5801-5804)
  The correspondence of Hans Hofmann consists mainly of incoming letters about personal and professional matters. Correspondents include museums, galleries, art dealers, collectors, former students, art historians, critics, fans, friends, and relatives. This series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and also includes a few subject files (e.g. "Autograph Requests," "Car Accident," and "War Compensation"). Although the date of Hofmann's reply is often noted on letters received, outgoing letters are limited to a small number of drafts and carbon copies. Because Hofmann's wife, Miz, often handled his business affairs and was friendly with his former students, many letters are addressed to her. Letters in foreign languages-mostly German, but some in Italian and French-are noted.
  Correspondents include Art of This Century Gallery (Peggy Guggenheim), Baltimore Museum of Art, Hofmann's dealer Samuel M. Kootz, the Museum of Modern Art, Mortimer Brandt Gallery (Betty Parsons), Betty Parsons Gallery, Howard Putzel of 67 Gallery, the Whitney Museum of American Art. Their letters document arrangements for Hofmann's major exhibitions and also concern the loan, sale, and donation of paintings.
  With the exception of a file titled "War Compensation," correspondence is limited to the years of Hofmann's residence in the United States. "War Compensation" correspondence and related records, 1912-1923, concern Hofmann's claim against the German government for personal property-including works of art-removed from his Paris apartment in 1914 while he was in Corsica. Correspondence documents attempts to learn the fate of his paintings and the claims process. Correspondents are painter Rudolph Levy, who may have sold Hofmann's paintings and possessions during the time he sublet the apartment; sculptor Eugen Steinhof, Monsieur Haven and Hermann Hailer, who would assist with the claim; and the Bund des Auslandsdeutschen, Bavarian Section. Supporting documentation consists of leases for his Paris apartment and a floorplan, drawn by Hofmann, that indicates placement of furniture and includes an inventory of possessions,including works of art, with values for each item.
  Small quantities of additional correspondence are filed with other series. School of Fine Arts Records (Series 2) include inquiries from prospective students, requests for transcripts and recommendations; Immigration and Naturalization Service approval of the school, correspondence about foreign students and correspondence with the Veterans Administration. Financial Records (Series 4) contain correspondence with the American Express Company, the Social Security Administration, and several banks. Estate Records (Series 9) include correspondence regarding taxes, Hofmann's Provincetown house, and legal matters concerning settlement of his estate. Papers of Renate Schmitz Hofmann (Series 10) include personal and estate correspondence, as well as condolence letters.
  - Harry N. Abrams, Incorporated, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Academia Tiberina (in Italian), 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Acme Laundry Company, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, Phillips Academy, 1947-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Adelphi College, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Advisory Committee on the Arts, Department of State (See: Department of State, Advisory Committee on the Arts) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Akademie der Bildenden Kunste in Nurnberg (in German), 1962-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Alberts, Jean Debran, 1955 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Albright Art Gallery, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Larry Aldrich Museum, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Allard Corporation, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Allied Artists of West Virginia, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Allied Publications, Inc., 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Ambassador of India, undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - American Council on Education, Committee on Leaders and Specialists, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1952-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - American Republic Insurance Company, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - American Society for Technion, Israel Institute of Technology, Inc., 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - American University, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Anderson-Mayer Gallery (See: Galerie Anderson-Mayer) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Andover Art Studio, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Apostolides, Zoe, 1960, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Architectural League of New York, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Archives of American Art, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Armstead, Jean, 1959 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Art Center Association, 1947 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Art Digest, 1930-1946 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1943-1963, undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Art International, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Art News, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Art of This Century, 1944 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Art Patrons League of Mobile, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Art Students League of New York, 1944, 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Artist Tenants Association, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - "Artists' Annual," 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Artists' Committee for Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Artists' Committee to Free Siquieros, 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1952 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Artists for CARE, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Arts & Architecture, 1945 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Arts Center Committee of Henry Street Settlement, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Arts Club of Chicago, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Artz, Mr., 1956-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Asher, Elise (See: Kunitz, Stanley and Elise Asher) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Ashton, Dore, 1960 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Atkins Museum of Fine Arts (See: William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Atlanta Art Institute, 1961 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Audubon Artists, Inc., 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Autograph Requests, 1958-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Axley, Martha F., 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - N. W. Ayer & Son, Inc., 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Balance, 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1953-1965, undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Barr, M.G. and R.V. Repogle, 1960, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bartas, Armand, Jr., undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - F.A. Bartlett Tree Expert Company, 1961, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bartok, Jean, 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bayerthal, F. L. (in German), 1962-1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Baziotes, William and Ethel, 1949 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Beale, Paulette, 1932-1959 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Beaumont, Mona, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bennington College, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Berg, Stephen, 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Berkman, Florence, 1957, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Berlad, Anne, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bevin, Alice C., 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bezirksfürsorgeverband München Stadt, Wohlfahrts-und Jugendamt (in German), 1934-1935 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Billmeyer, Willialm and Nieves, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Binder, Joseph and Carla, 1966, undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Birmingham Museum of Art, 1954, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bleich, Alan Ralph, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Blu Gallery (See: Galeria Blu) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Boakey, Dorothy, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Boaz, Helen, 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bogdonovitch, George J., 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Boloff's Catalogue of Modern Art, 1966 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bolmeier, Jane, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Booth, Cameron, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Boston Council for International Visitors, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bouchard, Diane, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Boxer, Jean, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bradley, Mary, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Brandeis University (See: Rose Art Museum) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Mortimer Brandt Gallery, 1946 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Brechemin, Louis, 1938-1939, undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Breeskin, Adelyn (See also: Baltimore Museum of Art; Washington Gallery of Modern Art),1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Brichter, Yela, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Brigadier, Anne and Maurice, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Brown, May and Everett, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Budnick, Sidney Gordon, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Buffalo Fine Arts Academy (See: Albright Art Gallery) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bultman, Fritz, 1963-1965, undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Bund des Auslandsdeutschen, Bavarian Section (See: War Compensation) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1946 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - California School of Fine Arts, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Car Accident, 1960 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Carles, Arthur B., 1934, undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1959 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Carosso, Roberta, 1961 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Louis Carré & Co. (See: Galerie Louis Carré & Co.) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Cassel, Frank, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Catalogo Internazionale dell'Arte Contemporanea (in Italian), 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Catalogue Integral des Travaux de Jean Dubuffet (in French), 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Catusco, Louis, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Caudell, Paul, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Cavallon, Giorgio and Linda, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Cerf, Phyllis (Mrs. Bennett), 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Channel 5, WABD, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Chapin, David and Barbara, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Chen, Jeannette, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Christ-Janner, Albert (See also: Pratt Institute), 1959 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Chrysler Art Museum of Provincetown, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Chrysler, Mr. and Mrs. Walter Percy, Jr., 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - City Center of Music and Drama, Inc., 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - City of New York, Fire Department, 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Clark, Lucile S. (Mrs. Alden Witcomb), 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Clarke, Allan Hugh, undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Clendenin, Eve, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Cleveland Center for the Arts, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Colin, Ralph J., Jr., undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Collectors Gallery, Inc., 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - College of Complexes, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Collier's Encyclopedia, 1960 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), 1963-1965, undated (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Connecticut Watercolor Society, Inc., 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Contemporary American Artists, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Contemporary Chamber Ensemble, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Contemporary Portfolios, Inc. (See also: Hollander Workshop Gallery), 1966 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Contemporary Slides, 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Copley, Alfred Lewin, 1945 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - CORE (See: Congress of Racial Equality) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Cornell University (See: John Dickson White Museum of Art) (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Creation in Form and Color correspondence with publishers and about copyright, 1931 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Raymond Creuze Tableaux Modernes (in French), 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Crotty, Frank H., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Cutler, Grayce E. (Grayce C. Solomon), 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1944, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Dane, Eva Maria, 1960 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Darling, Gilbert, 1944 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Dartmouth College, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Davidow, Rhoda (Mrs. Ernest P.), 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Davis, Ted, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Frank A. Days & Sons, 1959 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Dayton Art Institute, 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Delaney, Margaret (Mrs. Ward), 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Delgado Museum of Art, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Des Moines Art Center, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Department of State, Advisory Committee on the Arts, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Design Students Association, Institute of Design (Illinois Institute of Technology), 1958-1959 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Detre, Roland (in German), 1959 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, 1950 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Dick, Anna Gilles (Mrs. Nathan D.), 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Donnelley, Helen, 1944, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Donovan, Mr., 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Donovetsky, Ivan, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5801)
  - Donovetsky, Ivan, cont'd. 1957-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Douaihy, Saliba, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Dreyfuss, Lily (Mrs. William), 1963-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Dubuffet, Jean (in French), 1952, 1960 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Dudley Management Corp., 1959 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Duross Company (145 West 14th St. apartment), 1958-1960 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Eastman, Lee V., 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Edizioni d'Arte Fratelli Pozzo (in Italian), 1960-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Edwards, Oscar, 1954, 1961 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Edwards, Sibyl (Mrs. W. C., Jr.), 1963-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Eisenhart, Lucy, undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Ellsworth, Paul and Shirleen, 1949, 1960 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Exhibition Momentum, 1957 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Faltitschek, Joseph (partially in German), 1959-1964, undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Faulkner, Philippa, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Febich, Lynn Duke (Mrs. H. W.), 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Feinstein, Samuel L., 1952, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Ferdman, Joe, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fiedler, Arnold (in German), 1962-1964, undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Finch College Museum of Art, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fine, P., undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fischer, Wilhelm L., 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fleischman, Peri, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fleischmann, Katie, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fleiss, Max, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fletcher, Trudi, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Follett, Jean F., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Ford Foundation, 1958, 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fort Worth Art Center, 1959 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fortune, 1962 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Francis, Muriel, 1946, 1964, undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Frankenthaler, Helen (See: Motherwell, Robert and Helen Frankenthaler) (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Freed, Lillian and William, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Freeland, Clare (Mrs. Frank), 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Friborg, Stan and Dodie, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Friends of the Museum of Modern Art Emergency Committee, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Fullingly, Kurt, 1945 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Futter, Joy (Mrs. Thomas M.), 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Gahagan, James, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Galerie Anderson-Mayer, 1963-1965, undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Galerie des Artes (in German), 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Galerie Louis Carré Co., 1950 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Galerie Maeght (in French), 1952, undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Gallagher, Edward J., Jr., 1960 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Galleria Blu, 1963 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Geldzahler, Henry, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Germanisches National Museum (partially in German), 1959-1963, undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Gibson, Roland, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Glusman, Sidney, 1962-1965, undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Goetz, Amanda (in German), 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Golden, Barbara (Mrs. Stanley), 1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Goldwater, Robert, 1952 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Goodman, Laura, 1960 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Goodnough, Robert, 1960 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Gordon, H. Billings, undated (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Greenberg, Dorothy (Mrs. Sam), 1961-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Gregory, Bruce, 1958 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Guggenheim, Peggy (See: Art of This Century Gallery) (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Reel 5802)
  - Haddad, Jennie, 1958 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Haftmann, Werner (in German), 1959 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Hailer, Dr. Hermann (See: War Compensation) (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Haley, John, 1960-1964 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Hamilton, Frank O., 1960-1965, undated (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Hampton, Toni, 1961 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Harper's Bazaar, 1948 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Harriton, Abe and Estelle, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Hartigan, Grace (See: Price, Grace Hartigan) (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Harvard University, 1964 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Hasenecker, Maria, 1962 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Hauck, Janet (Mrs. Fred), 1960 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Haven, Monsieur (See: War Compensation) (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Hawthorne, Jo, 1952 (Box 2, Reel 5802)
  - Hayes, Bartlett, undated (Box 2, Reel 5802)